Register of the Walter Henry Judd papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- CONGRESSIONAL FILE, 1924-1983 (Box 61-156)
  - Mongolia, 1946-1961 (Box-folder 150: 3-5)
    Correspondence (including the State Department), memorandum, press release, speech, policy statement, notes, and clippings. Relates to Mongolian involvement in the Korean conflict and U.S. recognition of Outer Mongolia.
  - North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO), 1949-1968 (Box-folder 150: 6)
    Reports, treaty text, correspondence (including John Foster Dulles and Christian Herter), a printed article by John Kennedy, statements (including Dean Acheson and John Foster Dulles), notes, newsletter, pamphlet, and resolutions.
  - Pakistan, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 151: 1)
    Correspondence (including Ayub Khan and other Pakistani officials), reports, pamphlets, dispatch, notes, clippings, an interview and a speech by Ayub Khan, and statements by Aziz Ahmad. Primarily relates to India-Pakistan conflicts.
  - Philippines
    - General, 1943-1968 (Box-folder 151: 2)
      Printed matter, memorandum, speeches and statements (Carlos Romulo and Elpidio Quirino), and correspondence (including Manuel Quezon, Sergio Osmena, Carlos Romulo, and the State Department). Includes material relating to Carlos Romulo, Benigno Aquino, commerce, and development projects.
    - Philippine Rehabilitation Act, 1943-1962 (Box-folder 151: 3-4)
      Reports, draft and final legislation, statements, memoranda, correspondence (including the Philippine War Damage Commission), debates and hearing transcripts, and notes.
    - Resolution relating to Philippine independence, 1934-1944 (Box-folder 151: 5)
      Reports, draft and final copies of the resolution, printed statements (including Sergio Osmena, Manuel Quezon, and Franklin Roosevelt), correspondence (Manuel Quezon), memorandum, and notes.
    - Resolution relating to ship charters, 1953 (Box-folder 151: 6)
      Report, resolution, memoranda, and correspondence.
  - Poland, 1945-1980 (Box-folder 152: 1)
    Clippings, correspondence, printed material, reports, statements, and notes.
  - Russia
    - General, 1928-1963 (Box-folder 152: 2-3)
      Memoranda, report, testimony (Jay Lovestone), printed articles (including Anastas Mikoyan and Josef Stalin), newsletters, press releases, clippings, notes, pamphlets, speech, resolutions, miscellany, and correspondence. Includes material relating to the Comintern, party congresses, the Free Trade Union Committee of the AFL, religious persecution in the Ukraine, cultural exchange programs, and foreign relations.
    - Summit conferences, 1955-1961 (Box-folder 152: 4)
      Correspondence (including Christopher Emmet and a letter from Dr. Judd to Robert Murphy), printed matter (including articles by William Z. Foster, Joseph Alsop, and Thomas Dodd), press releases, notes, clippings, and reports. Relates to meetings in Geneva, Paris, and Vienna.
    - U-2 incident, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 152: 5)
      Correspondence, clippings, notes, memoranda, newsletters, and a draft of a note from Secretary of State Herter to the Soviet Foreign Minister. Includes material relating to the exchange of Francis Gary Powers for Rudolph Abel.
  - Science, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 152: 6)
    Debates, bills, and reports. Includes material relating to space and the National Science Foundation.
  - Spain, 1945-1975 (Box-folder 152: 7)
    Correspondence (including Spanish officials), clippings, and a memorandum.
  - Thailand, 1951-1957 (Box-folder 152: 8)
  - Trade
    - General, 1950-1962 (Box-folder 152: 9)
      Correspondence (including the State Department), memoranda, and miscellany.
    - Trade agreements, 1902-1962 (Box-folder 153: 1)
      Notes, clipping, debate transcripts, pamphlet, reports, statements (Dwight D. Eisenhower), draft legislation, charts, memoranda, press release, flyers, printed articles, and correspondence. Includes material relating to post-World War II reciprocal trade agreements and the General Agreement on Tariffs and Trade (GATT).
    - Trade Expansion bill, 1958-1962 (Box-folder 153: 2)
      Press release, correspondence (including a copy of a letter from Dwight D. Eisenhower), printed article, clipping, and reports.
  - United Nations
    - General, 1945-1978 (Box-folder 154: 1-3, Box-folder 153: 3-5)
      Draft legislation, reports, memoranda, press releases, notes, clippings, resolutions, hearing and debate transcripts, chart, statements (including John F. Kennedy and Francis Wilcox), chronologies, pamphlets, report, newsletters, and correspondence. Primarily relates to charter revision and U.S. purchase of U.N. bonds, as well as UNESCO, the expenses of military operations in the Congo, and the conferences at Dumbarton Oaks and Bretton Woods.
    - International Court of Justice, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 154: 4)
      Primarily correspondence relating to jurisdiction (Connally reservation).
    - International Labor Organization, 1949-1956 (Box-folder 154: 5)
      Constitution and rules, letter, notes, and a statement.
    - International Trade Organization, 1950 (Box-folder 154: 6)
    - Peace-keeping force, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 155: 1)
      Notes, resolutions (including one introduced by Dr. Judd), printed matter, and a statement. Includes material relating to the NATO treaty.
    - United Nations International Childrens Emergency Fund (UNICEF), 1947-1970 (Box-folder 155: 2)
      Correspondence, reports, clippings, statements (including Eleanor Roosevelt), pamphlets, fact sheet, newsletters, broadcast and hearing transcripts, and memoranda.
    - United Nations Relief and Rehabilitation Administration (UNRRA), 1945-1948 (Box-folder 155: 3)
    - World Health Organization, 1949-1979 (Box-folder 155: 4)
      Correspondence (including the State Department), reports, flyer, statements, memoranda, meeting reports, conference material, clippings, and charts. Includes material relating to birth control. See also: Legislation/80th Congress
  - Vatican, 1950-1952 (Box-folder 155: 5)
    Correspondence relating to the appointment of ambassadors.
  - Veterans, 1944-1962 (Box-folder 156: 1)
    Notes, draft and final legislation, clippings, fact sheets, and letters. Includes material relating to the GI Bill and other veterans benefits.
  - Vietnam and Southeast Asia, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 156: 2-3)
    Correspondence (including Thruston Morton, Cao Thai Bao, Raymond DeJaegher, the ICA, Carl W. Strom, and Hilaire du Berrier), printed matter, notes, a memorandum from Dr. Judd to Dwight Eisenhower, reports (Ngo Dinh Diem and Wolf Ladejinsky), and press releases. Includes material relating to Thailand and Cambodia.
  - Welfare and Social Security, 1946-1956 (Box-folder 156: 4)
    Reports, bills, notes, memoranda, newsletters, and correspondence.
  - World War II, 1943-1958 (Box-folder 156: 5)
    Correspondence, printed matter, memoranda, speeches and statements (including Franklin D. Roosevelt), press release, and notes. Includes material relating to the Cairo, Teheran, and Yalta conferences, war claims, and the Japanese-American Citizens League and internment claims.
  - Yugoslavia, 1946-1971 (Box-folder 156: 6)
    Correspondence, newsletters, notes, press releases, statements, serial issue, and report. Relates to foreign aid, Yugoslav relations with the U.S. and the U.S.S.R., and a proposed visit by Josip Tito to the U.S.
- CHINA FILE, 1922-1984 (Box 157-201)
  Correspondence, reports, position statements, resolutions, printed articles, newsletters, maps, clippings, press releases, flyers, pamphlets, serial issues, biographical material, speeches and statements, minutes, agendas, financial material, book reviews, memoranda, itineraries, conference material, petitions, bulletins, advertisements, transcripts, notes, and miscellany. Arranged alphabetically by subject.
  - General
    - Conditions in China, 1944-1979 (Box-folder 157: 1-3)
      Clippings, printed articles, reports, newsletters, miscellany, and a map. Primarily material by western travelers and analysts.
    - Clippings, 1947-1973 (Box-folder 157: 4)
      Relates to Dr. Judd.
    - Correspondence
      - General
        Includes letters from constituents relating to many of the issues itemized in this series.
        - 1943-1945 (Box-folder 157: 5)
        - 1945-1948 (Box-folder 158: 1-4)
        - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 159: 1-4)
        - 1950-1951 (Box-folder 160: 1-3)
        - 1951-1955 (Box-folder 161: 1-5)
        - 1956-1981 (Box-folder 162: 1-3)
        - Chinese government, 1942-1978 (Box-folder 162: 4)
          Includes legislators, the Embassy in Washington, and official information agencies.
        - Chinese news services, 1946-1969 (Box-folder 162: 5)
        - Organizations interested in China, 1939-1976 (Box-folder 162: 6)
        - Residents in China, 1944-1973 (Box-folder 163: 1-6)
          Primarily missionaries and other westerners.
        - U.S. government (primarily Congress), 1943-1974 (Box-folder 163: 7)
          Includes John McCormack, the White House, William Knowland, Charles Sawyer, and Karl Mundt.
        - U.S. news services, 1944-1961 (Box-folder 163: 8)
          Includes Irving R. Levine, Raymond Buell, and Edward Bliss.
      - Arnold, Julean, 1945 (Box-folder 163: 9)
      - Baker, John Earl, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 163: 10)
      - Benedict, Stephen, 1952-1953 (Box-folder 163: 11)
      - Buck, Pearl S., 1944-1945 (Box-folder 163: 12)
      - Bullitt, William C., 1950 (Box-folder 163: 13)
      - Chen, Chih-mai, 1947-1967 (Box-folder 163: 14)
        Includes a speech and reports on Communist-Kuomintang (KMT) relations and other subjects.
      - Chennault, Claire L. and Anna, 1948-1973 (Box-folder 163: 15)
        Includes printed matter.
      - Chiang, Ching-kuo, 1972-1981 (Box-folder 163: 16)
      - Chiang, Kai-shek and Chiang Soong Mei-ling, 1940-1982 (Box-folder 163: 17)
      - Chow, Shu-kai, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 164: 1)
      - Cooke, Charles M., Jr., 1948-1951 (Box-folder 164: 2)
      - Corcoran, Thomas G., 1952-1976 (Box-folder 164: 3)
      - Dewey, Thomas E., 1951 (Box-folder 164: 4)
        Includes a clipping.
      - Drumwright, Everett, 1975-1976 (Box-folder 164: 5)
      - Eden, Anthony, 1953-1954 (Box-folder 164: 6)
        Includes speeches.
      - Hahn, Emily, 1944 (Box-folder 164: 7)
      - Harlow, Bryce N., 1954 (Box-folder 164: 8)
      - Hurley, Patrick, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 164: 9)
      - Jaffe, Philip J., 1944 (Box-folder 164: 10)
      - Kohlberg, Alfred, 1944-1960 (Box-folder 164: 11-13)
        Includes correspondence with Bertrand Russell, Dean Acheson, John Carter Vincent, and others.
      - Koo, V. K. Wellington, 1947-1953 (Box-folder 165: 1)
        Includes a printed article.
      - Kung, H.H., 1948-1951 (Box-folder 165: 2)
      - Lattimore, Owen, 1943 (Box-folder 165: 3)
      - Leahy, William, 1947 (Box-folder 165: 4)
      - McConaughy, Walter P., 1974-1975 (Box-folder 165: 5)
      - Morley, Felix, 1947 (Box-folder 165: 6)
      - Mowrer, Edgar Ansel, 1957-1973 (Box-folder 165: 7)
      - Moyer, Raymond, 1943-1974 (Box-folder 165: 8)
        Includes related material. See Also: United States/Aid.
      - Neprud, Carl, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 165: 9)
      - Niebuhr, Reinhold, 1944 (Box-folder 165: 10)
      - Pee, Peter, 1947-1952 (Box-folder 165: 11)
      - Price, Frank W., 1945-1947 (Box-folder 165: 12)
      - Robertson, Walter, 1949-1970 (Box-folder 165: 13)
      - Rockefeller, John D., III, 1947 (Box-folder 165: 14)
      - Roosevelt, Edith Kermit, 1959-1960 (Box-folder 165: 15)
      - Shen, James C.H., 1972-1978 (Box-folder 165: 16)
      - Smedley, Agnes, 1943 (Box-folder 165: 17)
      - Van Fleet, James A., 1972-1975 (Box-folder 165: 18)
      - Walker, Richard L., 1958-1960 (Box-folder 165: 19)
      - Wedemeyer, Albert C., 1945-1983 (Box-folder 165: 20)
      - Wigglesworth, Richard B., 1958-1959 (Box-folder 165: 21)
      - Yarnell, H.E., 1949 (Box-folder 165: 22)
    - Notes, 1945-1953 (Box-folder 165: 23)
      Relates to meetings with Harry Truman, Dwight Eisenhower, James Byrnes, Dean Acheson, Charles Bohlen, George Kennan, Omar Bradley, and others.
  - Agriculture and land reform, 1944-1975 (Box-folder 165: 24)
    Speech, clippings, reports, serial issues, and a press release.
  - Aid to Refugee Chinese Intellectuals
    - General, 1952-1959 (Folder 25)
      Clippings, report, newsletters, notes, by-laws, and miscellany.
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1951-1980 (Box-folder 166: 1-4, Box-folder 167: 1-3)
        Includes Anthony Eden, Dwight Eisenhower, Philip Jessup, Roscoe Pound, J. Howard Pew, John Lodge, Margaret Sanger, Harold Stassen, Jacob Javits, E.F. Hutton, Bernard Baruch, H.E. Yarnell, George Marshall, H.H. K'ung, Chen Chi-mai, Leighton Stuart, Nelson Rockefeller, Charles Edison, Allen Dulles, Henry R. Luce, John Sparkman, J. Peter Grace, Stanley Hornbeck, Thruston Morton, Paul Douglas, Arthur Bliss Lane, Chester Nimitz, Claire Chennault, H.J. Kaiser, Charles Cooke, Edwin N. Clark, Lucius Clay, Bruce Pirnie, various U.S. government agencies, and non-profit organizations.
      - Internal, 1951-1970 (Box-folder 167: 4-5, Box-folder 169: 1-4, Box 168)
        Includes memoranda and correspondence by Ernest Moy, Marvin Liebman, Harold Oram, Karl Compton, Christopher Emmet, and B.A. Garside.
    - Financial material, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 169: 5)
      Budgets, memoranda, charts, reports, and correspondence.
    - Meeting minutes and agenda, 1952-1969 (Box-folder 170: 1-3)
    - Membership material, 1951-1952 (Box-folder 170: 4)
      Primarily lists.
    - Reports, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 171: 1-2)
      Includes material relating to refugees and conditions in Hong Kong.
    - Statements and program descriptions, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 171: 3)
      Speeches, press releases, pamphlets, and miscellany.
  - American-Asian Educational Exchange, 1957-1981 (Box-folder 171: 4, Box-folder 172: 1-2)
    Subsequently the American Afro-Asian Educational Exchange. Memoranda, draft articles of incorporation, correspondence (including Ralph de Toledano, G. Mennen Williams, Walter S. Robertson, John D. Rockefeller, III, and Stanley Hornbeck), minutes, pamphlet, conference material, printed matter (including a speech by Chiang Kai-shek), form letters, reports, and miscellany.
  - American Bureau for Medical Aid to China, 1939-1984 (Box-folder 174: 1, Box 173, Box-folder 172: 3)
    Correspondence, newsletters, reports, pamphlets, agenda and minutes, printed matter, and miscellany. Includes letters from Cordell Hull, Claire Chennault, J. Howard Pew, Alfred Kohlberg, Joseph Ball, Arthur Radford, and Walter Robertson.
  - American China Policy Association, 1946-1960 (Box-folder 174: 2)
    Correspondence, clippings and other printed matter, press releases, and a flyer. See Also: Correspondence/Kohlberg, Alfred.
  - Asia Foundation, 1953-1957 (Box-folder 174: 3)
    Formerly Committee for Free Asia. Correspondence, statement of purpose, and printed matter.
  - Asian Peoples Anti-communist League, 1955-1976 (Box-folder 174: 4)
    Correspondence, conference report, and printed matter.
  - Center for Strategic and International Studies, 1978-1984 (Box-folder 174: 5)
    Reports, correspondence, and printed matter.
  - Chiang Ching, 1974-1977 (Box-folder 174: 6)
    Clippings, biographical material, and a speech.
  - Chiang Ching-kuo, 1954-1982 (Box-folder 174: 7)
    Speeches, correspondence, clippings, interviews, and biographical material.
  - Chiang Kai-shek and Chiang Soong Mei-ling, 1930-1984 (Box-folder 175: 1-4)
    Speeches, clippings, newsletters, printed articles, press releases, book review, serial issue, pamphlets, biographical material, and correspondence (including James C.H. Shen (Shen Ch'ang-huan), Robert Strong, Hollington Tong, and Raymond Moyer). Note that this material relates to Chiang Kai-shek and Chiang Soong Mei-ling; correspondence with them is located primarily in Correspondence/Chiang, Kai-shek and Chiang Soong Mei-ling.
  - China Emergency Committee, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 175: 5)
    Subsequently the Committee to Defend America by Aiding Anti-Communist China. Correspondence, clippings, memorandum, statements (including Pat McCarran, William Green, Fred McKee, Charles Edison and Claire Chennault), press releases, and miscellany.
  - China Institute in America, 1943-1955 (Box-folder 175: 6)
  - Chou En-lai, 1938-1976 (Box-folder 175: 7)
    Printed articles, biographical material, flyer, newsletters, clippings, and a press release.
  - Christianity and missions, 1945-1981 (Box-folder 176: 1)
    Minutes, reports, notes, correspondence, clippings, newsletters, and a booklet. Includes material relating to communist persecution. See also: General/Correspondence/General/Residents in China.
  - Civil rights and dissent, 1955-1979 (Box-folder 176: 2)
    Report, clippings, newsletters, and miscellany. Includes material relating to the refusal of U.S. officials to grant exit visas to Chinese students.
  - Clergymen's Committee on China, Inc., 1966-1970 (Box-folder 176: 3)
    Correspondence (including DeWitt Wallace), press release, memorandum, and miscellany.
  - Coalition for Asian Peace and Security, 1979-1980 (Box-folder 176: 4)
    Press releases, correspondence, clippings, and a statement (S.I. Hayakawa).
  - Commerce and industry, 1943-1972 (Box-folder 176: 5)
    Printed articles, newsletters, and reports.
  - Committee for a Democratic Far Eastern Policy, 1945-1950 (Box-folder 176: 6)
    Previously Committee for a Democratic Policy toward China. Correspondence, bulletins, resolutions, and conference material.
  - Committee of One Million
    Subsequently Committee for a Free China.
    - General
      - Non-printed material, 1953-1983 (Box 177, Box-folder 176: 7-8, Box-folder 178: 1-2)
        Minutes, agenda, reports, position statements, financial and fund-raising material, lists, speeches (including Thomas J. Dodd and Joseph Grew), resolutions, conference material, itineraries, petitions, and open letters (to President Eisenhower and others).
      - Printed material
        - General, 1951-1977 (Box-folder 179: 1, Box-folder 178: 3-4)
          Reports, speeches (including Dean Rusk, Paul Douglas, Joseph Grew, and Peter Dominick), pamphlets, advertisements, clippings, book reviews, newsletters, flyers, declarations, letters to editors, and petitions.
        - China Report newsletters, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 179: 2)
    - Correspondence
      - General, 1953-1983 (Box 180, Box-folder 179: 3-5)
        Includes Herbert Hoover, Sherman Adams, John Foster Dulles, Allen Dulles, Harry S. Truman, Albert C. Wedemeyer, Claire Chennault, Stanley Hornbeck, Walter Robertson, William F. Buckley, Henry R. Luce, J. Howard Pew, Spruille Braden, Cyrus Eaton, Karl Rankin, and numerous members of Congress (including Gerald Ford, Jacob Javits, Hubert Humphrey, Robert Dole, Hiram Fong, Strom Thurmond, Barry Goldwater, J.W. Fulbright, and Robert Byrd).
      - Internal
        - General, 1953-1981 (Box-folder 183: 1-2, Box 181-182)
          Includes Joseph Grew, Paul Douglas, Warren Austin, Thomas J. Dodd, Ernest F. Hollings, Peter H. Dominick, John McCormack, Jesse Helms, Walter McConaughy, H. Alexander Smith, Christopher Emmet, Frederick McKee, Charles A. Edison, and Marvin Liebman.
        - De Rochefort, Nicholas, 1953-1962 (Box-folder 183: 3)
          Includes reports and miscellany relating to Russia and to propaganda techniques.
  - Communism, 1938-1981 (Box-folder 184: 1-2)
    Pamphlets, reports (including Louis Budenz, Stanley Hornbeck, Freda Utley, various missionaries, and the U.S. War Department), correspondence (including Clare Boothe Luce), book reviews, newsletters, printed articles, clippings, serial issues, and a book entitled The Happy Youth of China; includes issues and supplements of China Reconstructs.
  - Communist Party U.S.A., 1937-1949 (Box-folder 184: 3)
    Statements (including William Z. Foster, Mao Tse-tung, Clare Boothe Luce, and Earl Browder), memoranda, and clippings.
  - Cultural Revolution, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 184: 4)
    Clippings, newsletters, a report, and printed articles.
  - Culture and society, 1949-1975 (Box-folder 184: 5)
    Newsletters, clippings, and printed articles. Includes material relating to Confucianism and ethnic minorities in China.
  - Democratic League, 1947 (Box-folder 184: 6)
    Correspondence, reports, and newsletters.
  - Drugs, 1949-1974 (Box-folder 184: 7)
    Clippings, printed articles, correspondence, reports, press releases, and newsletters.
  - Economics, currency and finance, 1944-1965 (Box-folder 185: 1)
    Clippings, reports (including Chou En-lai), correspondence, and newsletters.
  - Education, 1949-1974 (Box-folder 185: 2)
    Printed articles, press releases, and a report.
  - Emergency Committee for Chinese Refugees, 1962 (Box-folder 185: 3)
    Subsequently Chinese Refugee Relief. Correspondence, statement (Anna Chennault), flyer, and miscellany.
  - Feng Yu-hsiang, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 185: 4)
    Correspondence, clippings, biographical material, and a newsletter.
  - Foreign relations
    See also: Russia, United States, and United Nations.
    - General, 1922-1979 (Box-folder 185: 5)
      Reports, clippings, newsletters, press releases, printed articles, speeches (including Huang Hua and Mao Tse-tung), a memorandum, notes, pamphlets, and a copy of a treaty. Includes material relating to the issue of recognition of communist China.
    - Asia, 1948-1975 (Box-folder 185: 6)
      Clippings, press releases, correspondence (including Chen Chih-mai), notes, and reports. Includes material relating to India and Southeast Asia.
  - Free China Fund, 1954-1958 (Box-folder 185: 7-8)
    Reports, printed material, and correspondence (including Claire Chennault, Joseph Grew, V.K. Wellington Koo, Lucius Clay, Henry R. Luce, J. Leighton Stuart, Sherman Adams, Matthew Ridgway, Walter Bedell Smith, H.H. K'ung, and Arthur Radford).
  - Free Pacific Association, Asian Speakers Bureau, 1965-1980 (Box-folder 186: 1)
    Correspondence (including Raymond DeJaegher) and printed material.
  - Friends of Free China, 1966-1984 (Box-folder 186: 2)
    Newsletters, correspondence, clippings, and miscellany.
  - Hong Kong, 1952-1970 (Box-folder 186: 3)
    Clippings, newsletter, correspondence, reports, statements, and printed material. Primarily relates to refugees.
  - Hundred Flowers movement, 1957 (Box-folder 186: 4)
    Printed material, including On the Correct Handling of Contradictions Among the People, by Mao Tse-tung.
  - Institute of Pacific Relations, 1939-1970 (Box-folder 186: 5-6)
    Clippings, correspondence, serial issue, press releases, reports, printed articles, and notes. Includes material relating to the Amerasia case.
  - Lin Piao, 1965-1974 (Box-folder 186: 7)
    Report, clippings, press releases, newsletters, printed articles, and pamphlets.
  - Mao Tse-tung, 1949-1979 (Box-folder 186: 8)
    Printed articles, pamphlets, speeches (including Barry Goldwater), clippings, letter (William Knowland), and newsletters. Includes speeches and writings by Mao Tse-tung.
  - Military, 1946-1970? (Box-folder 186: 9)
    Correspondence, reports, pamphlets, newsletter, and clippings. See also: Taiwan.
  - Politics and government
    - Republic of China
      - General, 1930-1950 (Box-folder 187: 1-2)
        Report, correspondence, pamphlets, clippings, chart, biographical material, newsletters, press releases, printed articles (including Paul M.A. Linebarger), and speeches (including Chiang Kai-shek).
      - Communist-controlled areas, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 187: 3)
        Clippings, report, and a pamphlet entitled Annual Report of the Shensi-Kansu-Ninghsia Border Region Government, by Lin Tsu-han.
      - Kuomintang-Communist relations, 1939-1949 (Box-folder 187: 4)